KABIR GREWAL

kgrewal7777@gmail.com (330) 714 7845 <u>LinkedIn</u>

Summary

Software Developer with 2 years of co-op work experience, rated "Excellent" or better from each employer. Quickly adapts to new environments and tech stacks. Experience with Application and Web Development as well as DevOps engineering. Creative problem-solver who can work independently or collaborate with a team. Seeking employment opportunities that feature continually improving development philosophy and opportunities to engage with emerging technologies.

Education

Bachelor of Computer Science with a Political Science Minor from the University of Waterloo.

Skills and Technologies

- ❖ Object-Oriented programming with Python, C++, Java
- ❖ Web Dev: JavaScript, CSS, PHP, Nginx, Angular
- ❖ Server Management for Linux and Windows
- ❖ CI/CD implemented with Ansible, Docker, Jenkins
- Continuous Monitoring and Feedback through Elasticsearch, Kibana, Grafana, Zabbix

Work Experience

CGI Canada Wealth360 Division, DevOps Engineer: April 2018 – December 2018

- ❖ maintained and implemented CI/CD pipelines for the DevOps Team
- ❖ administered and improved the division's Atlassian toolset, automating the migration and integration of local user accounts to an existing AD using Atlassian Server APIs for example
- ❖ independently researched, presented, and implemented a server monitoring solution (Zabbix)
- engaged with DevOps philosophy through practical experience and workshop presentations

Viryl Technologies, Web Developer: August 2017 – December 2017

- ❖ built new and improved existing features for Viryl's ADAPT website using JS, CSS, and PHP
- ❖ implemented processes to improve workflow (Gitflow, Agile principles, Post-Get-Redirect)
- collaborated with stakeholders and team members to gather requirements and feedback
- took on a leadership role by organizing development and testing strategies to meet sprint goals

Bonfire Interactive, Web Developer: January 2017 – April 2017

- ❖ learned JS, CSS, Angular 2 and PHP as a full stack programmer
- participated in an Agile environment, and engaged in all steps of the software development lifecycle
- delivered several independent projects, including a historical project timeline for the company
- ❖ gained Dev-Ops experience by provisioning a micro-service using AWS, Redis, Ansible, and Nginx
- * adapted to a time-sensitive start-up development environment focused on meeting deadlines

Bank of America Merrill Lynch: August 2015 - December 2015 and April 2016 - August 2016

- gained Python coding skills and techniques for the AMPS messaging system
- independently developed and presented a demo for upcoming queue functionality within AMPS
- completed other projects, including a scheduled, automated AMPS instance restart system
- gained user and client support experience by interacting with and aiding other AMPS users
- orchestrated remote deployment/management of these performance testing suites using Ansible
- submitted the team's benchmarking use case as a possible integration testing solution